The white zone is for loading
and unloading of passengers only.
白色区是乘客上落专用区
There is no stopping in the red zone.
不准停在红色区
The white zone is for loading
and unloading of passengers only.
白色区是乘客上落专用区
There is no stopping in the red zone.
不准停在红色区
The white zone is for loading
and unloading of passengers only.
白色区是乘客上落专用区
There is no stopping in the red zone.
不准停在红色区
The white zone is for loading
and unloading of passengers only.
白色区是乘客上落专用区
There is no stopping in the red zone.
不准停在红色区
Hello. Take this flower from
the Religious Consciousness Church.
你好，请收下醒悟教的花朵
- Would you care to make a donation?
- No, but thank you anyway.
-可否捐献？
-不了，但谢谢你的花
The red zone is for loading
and unloading of passengers only.
红色区是乘客上落专用区
There is no stopping in the white zone.
不准停在白色区
No. The white zone
is for loading and unloading.
白色区才是乘客上落专用区
There's no stopping in the red zone.
不准停在红色区才对
The red zone's always been
for loading and unloading.
红色区一直是乘客上落专用区
There's never stopping in a white zone.
不准停留的一直是白色区
Don't tell me which zone is for
stopping and which is for loading.
别告诉我哪区是上落区
Listen, Betty, don't start up
with your white zone shit again.
别又再说那些白色区废话了
Hello. Take this flower from
the Religious Consciousness Church.
你好，请收下醒悟教的花朵
- Would you like to make a donation?
- No, thanks. We gave at the office.
-可否捐献？
-不，我们在办公室已捐献了
Would you put all your metal objects
into this dish, please?
请把金属物件放在盘上
There's just no stopping
in a white zone.
白色区是不许停下的
Really, Vernon, why pretend?
你别装蒜了
We both know
what you're talking about.
你在说什么大家心知肚明
You want me to have an abortion.
你想我坠胎
It's the only sensible thing to do.
If it's done properly,
只要小心行事，这是最佳方法
therapeutically,
there's no danger involved.
基本上并不危险
Taxi!
的士！
I'll be back in a minute.
我很快回来
Hello, sir, take this flower from
the Religious Consciousness Church.
先生，请收下醒悟教的花朵
Would you care...
你可否…
- Hey, Larry, where's the forklift?
- Forklift?
-莱利，铲车呢？
-铲车？
It's over there
by the baggage loader.
在那边，行李装机旁
Look out!
小心！
- Elaine.
- Ted!
-绮莲
-泰德！
I came home early
and found your note.
我早了回家，看到你的便条
I guess you meant for me
to read it later. I've got to talk to you.
你大概是想我稍后才看到
我得和你谈谈
I don't want to go over it any more.
我不想再说了
Things haven't been right
for a long time,
我知道很多事是日积月累的
but it'll be different,
like in the beginning.
但一定会有所改变
就像开始时那样
Just be patient
and I'll work things out.
请有点耐性，我会想办法
I have been patient
and I've tried to help,
我一直都很有耐性
并尝试去帮助你
but you wouldn't even let me do that.
但你甚至不让我这样做
Don't you feel anything for me
any more?
你对我已没有感觉？
It takes so many things
to make love last.
令爱情长久，要有很多因素
Most of all, it takes respect.
最重要是彼此尊重
I can't live with a man
I don't respect!
我不能与我不尊重的人生活
What a pisser.
真惹人讨厌
(小说)
(非小说)
(怪诞材料)
(现代精子)
Captain Oveur, white courtesy phone.
欧机长，请接听白色电话
Captain Clarence Oveur,
white courtesy phone.
欧家伦机长，请听白色电话
No, the white phone!
不，白色电话才对
This is Captain Oveur.
我是欧机长
One moment for your call
from the Mayo Clinic.
美奥诊所找你
Captain Oveur, white courtesy phone.
欧机长，请听白色电话
- I've got it!
- Thank you.
-我已在接听
-谢谢
Go ahead with your call.
请接来
This is Dr Brody at the Mayo Clinic.
我是美奥诊所的布医生
There's a passenger
on your Chicago flight,
在你往芝加哥的航机上
有一名乘客
a little girl named Lisa Davis,
en route to Minneapolis.
一个叫戴莉莎的小女孩
是前往明尼阿波利斯的
She's scheduled
for a heart transplant.
她正排期接受心脏移植手术
Tell her mother we found a donor.
告诉她母亲我们找到捐赠者
The heart is ready for surgery.
心脏已准备好移植
We must have the recipient on
the operating table within six hours.
手术得在六小时内进行
Make sure she's kept
in a reclined position,
确保她要躺着
and that a continuous watch
is kept on her IV.
并一直接受静脉注射
It's very important she remain calm...
她保持冷静是很重要的
Excuse me, this is the operator.
对不起，我是接线生
I have an emergency call on line five
from a Mr Hamm.
韩先生急电，在第五线
Give me Hamm on five, hold the Mayo.
替我接进来
You'll be back tomorrow night.
We'll have dinner. We'll talk things over.
你明晚会回来
到时我们共进晚餐好好谈谈
I won't be back.
I've requested the Atlanta run.
我不会回来
我要求调往阿特兰大
Elaine... I promise I can change.
绮莲，我保证我可以改变
Then why didn't you take the job
that Louie Netz offered you at Boeing?
那么为何你不接受李路易
在波音公司给你的工作？
I haven't been able to get
near a plane since the war.
战后我无法走近飞机
And they wouldn't hire me
because of my war record.
加上我的战时记录
他们不会聘用我的
War record? You're the only one
keeping that alive.
战时记录？只有你才在意
For everyone else,
it's ancient history.
其他人都不当这是一回事
- You expect me to believe that?
- It's the truth.
-你以为我会相信？
-那是事实
What's hurt you the most
is your record since the war -
最丢人的是你战后的记录
different cities, different jobs -
往不同城市，做不同工作
and not one of them shows you
can accept any real responsibility.
完全显示了你不可以承担责任
- Elaine, just give me one more...
- It's too late, Ted.
-绮莲，再给我一次…
-太迟了
When I get back to Chicago,
当我返回芝加哥
I'm going to start my life
all over again. I'm sorry.
我要重新生活，抱歉
Excuse me, take this flower
from the Church of Religious...
请收下醒悟教的花朵
Hi! Well, good evening.
你好
There you go.
Just follow them to the back.
行了，跟着他们
Any word on that storm lifting
over Salt Lake, Clarence?
有没有盐湖城那风暴消息？
No, not likely, Victor.
没有
I just reviewed the area report
for 1600 hours through 2400.
我刚看过四点至十二点的
地区报告
There's an occluded front
stalled over the Dakotas,
有一道冷锋在达科他上
backed up all the way to Utah.
一直伸展至犹他
If she decides to push over the Great
Lakes, it could get plenty soupy.
若移至大湖区，就会很大雾
What about that southern route
around Tulsa?
走南路绕过图沙又如何？
I double-checked
the terminal forecast,
我已查看过了
and the wind's aloft
and IFR ceilings all the way.
天气同样恶劣
Where do they top out?
如何恶劣？
Light scattered cover at 20,000,
icing around 18.
二万英尺高空满布密云
一万八千英尺高空更有冰雹
- Looks like over Denver is best.
- Denver it is.
-似乎丹佛的天气最好
-是的
Sorry, Clarence.
抱歉
Latest report shows everything's
socked in from Salt Lake to Lincoln.
最新报告显示由盐湖城至林肯
都很大雾
Hi, Roger. Glad to have you aboard.
罗渣，欢迎你
Victor, this is Roger Murdock.
Victor Basta.
伟达，这是梅罗渣，白伟达
- How do you do?
- Nice to meet you.
-你好吗？
-幸会
I was telling Victor
I reviewed the area report
我正跟伟达说
我看过四点至十二点的…
for 1600 hours through 2400.
地区报告
There's an occluded front
stalled over the Dakotas.
有一道冷锋在达科他上
(美国新闻选举影响)
There you go. Thank you.
行了，谢谢
Is Elaine Dickinson on this flight?
请问狄绮莲在这班机上吗？
The whole flight crew has boarded.
Let me see.
所有机员都登机了，让我看看
Oh, yes. She is on board.
对，她在机上
I'd like one ticket to Chicago.
No baggage.
我想要一张往芝加哥的机票
没有行李
- Smoking or non-smoking?
- Smoking, please.
-吸烟抑或不吸烟？
-吸烟
There. Have a nice trip.
这里，祝旅程愉快
Striker, this is Red Leader Four.
史泰德，这是红队长四号
Primary target covered by fog.
主要目标被大雾遮盖
Decision to proceed is yours.
你要决定继续进行
The decision is yours...
是你决定…
is yours... is yours...
是你…
那白人该远离我妻子
否则我会揍他
对，他不该这样做
我认识一个处境相同的人
结果他后悔莫及
别那么天真了，雅瑟
我们每人都有道德选择
早睡早起
令人健康、富足和聪明
说得真好！
(请勿吸烟)
(扣紧安全带)
Nervous?
很紧张？
Yes.
是的
First time?
第一次？
No. I've been nervous lots of times.
不，已很多次
Hi. We'll be taking off real soon,
so I better fasten you in tight.
我们快起飞了
我替你扣好安全带吧
Thank you.
Oh, Mother, this is so exciting!
劳驾，妈妈，我很兴奋
I know, but remember,
you must get some rest.
我知道，但你得休息
That's good advice. You relax,
and I'll be back after we take off.
你放松点吧！
飞机起飞后我会再回来
Thank you.
谢谢你
- I'm going to miss you so much.
- I'm going to miss you, too.
-我会很想念你
-我也是
Promise you'll write?
答应我写信给我
Every day.
每天都会
Bill!
阿标！
Better get on board, son.
快登机吧
All aboard!
所有乘客登机
209er to ground control.
We're ready to taxi.
209号班机叫地面指挥
我们准备起程
- Goodbye, Bill!
- Goodbye, darling!
-再见，阿标
-再见，宝贝
I love you, darling!
我爱你
209er, taxi to runway19er.
209号班机
请使用第19号跑道
Goodbye, darling!
再见，宝贝
Have your picture taken the minute
you get there and send me one.
你一到步
就要拍照并立即寄给我
OK. Here, hurry.
好的，拿着
It's your watch. You shouldn't.
You're going to need this.
这是你的手表，你不该给我
你会用得着的
It's all right. It doesn't work.
不要紧，已坏掉
- Bill!
- Goodbye, darling!
-阿标
-再见，宝贝
Bill!
阿标！
Bill! Bill!
I'll keep it with me all the time.
阿标，我会整天戴着它
- Flight 209er- clear for takeoff.
- Roger.
-209号班机，可以起飞
-收到
- LA departure frequency 123.9er.
- Roger.
-洛杉矶离开频道是123.9
-收到
- Request vector. Over.
- What?
-请给航向指示
-什么？
Flight 209er, clear for vector 324.
209号班机，可以起飞了
- We have clearance, Clarence.
- Roger, Roger.
-我们可以起飞了
-收到
What's our vector, Victor?
伟达，航向指示是什么？
- I want radio clearance. Over.
- That's Clarence Oveur. Over.
-我想要无线电指示
-我是欧家伦
- Roger.
- Huh?
-收到
-什么？
- Roger. Over.
- Huh? Who?
-收到？
-谁？
Do you feel all right, sir?
先生，你没事吧？
Oh, I haven't flown for a long time.
我很久没有乘搭飞机了
Good evening.
This is Captain Oveur speaking.
各位好，我是欧机长
We'll be cruising
at 36,000 feet this evening...
我们今晚会在
三万六千英尺上空飞行
(男孩生活)
(修女生活)
Relax and enjoy your flight.
放松，好好享受今次旅程
Would you like something to read?
想看点什么吗？
Do you have anything light?
有没有轻松一些的？
How about this leaflet,
"Famous Jewish Sports Legends"?
“著名犹太运动巨星”
册子如何？
Yes. Thank you.
好的，劳驾
- Ted! What are you doing here?
- I've got to talk to you.
-泰德，你为何会在这里？
-我得和你谈谈
You shouldn't have come.
I don't have time now.
你不该上机，我现在没时间
- Stewardess?
- Excuse me.
-小姐？
-失陪
No wonder you're upset. She's lovely.
难怪你不开心，她很可爱
And a darling figure.
身材又好
Supple, pouting breasts, firm thighs.
肌肤充满弹性，丰乳纤腿
It's a shame you two
don't get along.
可惜你俩合不来
Yes, I know.
我知道
Things used to be different.
以前并不是这样的
I remember when we first met.
我记得我们首次相遇的情形
It was during the war.
是战时的事
I was in the air force, stationed in
Drambuie, off the Barbary Coast.
我加入空军
驻守巴巴利海岸的杜林比
I used to hang out
at the Magumba Bar.
经常往马金巴酒吧
It was a rough place.
The seediest dive on the wharf,
那是一处品流复杂的地方
populated with every reject and
cut-throat from Bombay to Calcutta.
三山五岳的人都聚集在那儿
It was worse than Detroit.
比底特律还要差
The mood in the place was ugly.
那儿的气氛也不好
You wouldn't be there unless
you knew how to use your fists.
拳头要够硬才可以往那里
A fight broke out almost every night.
几乎每晚都会发生打斗
I didn't go there that night to fall in love.
I just wanted a couple of drinks.
我并非往那里找情人
只想喝几杯
And suddenly, there she was.
突然之间，我看到她
I was captivated, entranced.
It hit me like a thunderbolt.
我完全被她俘虏，像遭电击
I had to ask this guy to pinch me
to make sure I wasn't dreaming.
我得叫这厮捏我
以确保自己不是在做梦
I was afraid to approach her,
我害怕上前认识她
but that night, fate was on my side.
但那晚，我们注定相识
We laughed, we talked, we danced.
我们谈天、说笑和跳舞
I never wanted it to end.
I guess I still don't.
我不想那晚结束，现在亦然
Enough about me. I hope
this hasn't been boring for you.
我说够了，希望没把你闷坏
But whenever I talk about Elaine, I get
so carried away. I lose all track of time.
但每当说起绮莲，我都很投入
浑然忘记了时间
Would you like to order dinner?
想要晚餐吗？
- Joey will have steak. We'll have fish.
- When can I see the cockpit?
-祖儿吃牛扒，我们则吃鱼
-我何时可以参观驾驶舱？
The pilots are probably too busy
flying the plane for that.
机师现在很忙
Aw, gee whizz!
真气人！
I'll talk to the captain
and see what I can arrange.
我跟机长说，且看能否安排
Gee, that'd be swell!
太好了！
Would you care to order your dinners?
想吃晚餐吗？
我想吃牛扒
我要鱼
Excuse me, I happened to be passing.
我刚巧经过
I thought you might like some coffee.
你要咖啡吗？
That's very nice of you. Thank you.
你真有心，谢谢
- Won't you sit down?
- Thank you.
-坐吧
-谢谢
- Cream?
- No, I take it black.
-加奶吗？
-不，我喝黑咖啡的
Like my men.
像我的男人一样
Ted, I never knew
I could be so happy.
泰德，我实在太快乐了
These past few months
have been wonderful.
这几个月简直是神仙生活
Tomorrow, why don't we drive
to that little seafood place and...
不如明天我们去吃海鲜
- What's the matter?
- My orders came through.
-怎么了？
-我接到命令
My squadron ships out tomorrow.
我的部队要明天出发
We're bombing the storage depots
at Daiquiri at 1800 hours.
我们要在六点钟
轰炸戴基利的补给站
We're coming in from the north,
below their radar.
我们由北面进袭
低于他们的雷达
- When will you be back?
- I can't tell you that. It's classified.
-你何时回来？
-我不能说，是机密
Oh, Ted, please be careful.
I worry about you so much.
泰德，万事小心，我很担心
I love you, Elaine.
我爱你，绮莲
I love you.
我爱你
Flight 209er,
this is Denver flight control.
209号班机，这是丹佛控制塔
You're approaching rough weather.
Please climb to 42,000 feet.
前面天气并不稳定
请上升至四万二千英尺
- Roger, Denver.
- We have a visitor.
-收到
-有访客到
Hello.
你好
Captain Oveur, Mr Murdock,
and Mr Basta, this is Joey Hammen.
欧机长、梅先生、白先生
这是夏祖儿
- Hi, Joey.
- Come up here.
-祖儿，你好
-过来
This is for special visitors.
Would you like to have it?
这是送给访客的，想要吗？
- Thank you. Thanks a lot.
- Sure. Ever been in a cockpit?
-实在谢谢你
-别客气，到过驾驶舱没有？
No, I've never been up
in a plane before.
没有，我从没乘搭过飞机
Have you ever seen
a grown man naked?
你见过成年男性裸体吗？
- Shall I check the weather?
- No, why don't you take care of it?
-该看看天气吗？
-不，你负责吧
Joey, do you ever hang around
the gymnasium?
祖儿，你有否到过体操馆？
- We'd better get back.
- No, Joey can stay for a while.
-我们还是回去吧
-不，祖儿可以多留一会
- Could I?
- OK, if you don't get in the way.
-真的？
-只要你不碍事便行
Flight 209er to Denver,
climbing to cruise at 42,000.
209号班机叫丹佛控制塔
我们升至四万二千英尺上空前进
We'll report again over Lincoln.
Over and out.
我们到林肯上空时会再报到
Wait a minute, I know you.
You're Kareem Abdul Jabbar.
慢着，我认得你，你是渣巴
You play basketball
for the Los Angeles Lakers.
效力洛杉矶湖人队的
Sorry, you have me confused
with someone else.
抱歉，你认错人了
My name's Roger Murdock.
I'm the co-pilot.
我叫梅罗渣，是副机师
You are Kareem! I've seen you play.
My dad's got season tickets.
你是渣巴，我看过你比赛
我爸买了季票
You should go back to your seat now.
Right, Clarence?
你该返回座位，对吗？家伦
No, he's not bothering anyone.
Let him stay here.
不，他没骚扰任何人
让他留下
All right, but just remember
my name is Roger Murdock.
好，但记着，我叫做梅罗渣
I'm an airline pilot.
是个机师
I think you're the greatest,
我觉得你是最出色的球员
but my dad says you don't work
hard enough on defence.
但爸说你在防守方面做得不够
And he says lots of times
you don't even run downcourt.
他经常说你甚至不回防
And you don't try,
except during the play-offs.
在季后赛时才偶尔回防
The hell I don't!
我有回防的！
Listen, kid, I've been hearing that crap
ever since I was at UCLA.
自从我在大学开始
已不断听到这种废话
I'm out there busting my buns
every night.
我每晚都尽力比赛
Tell your old man
to drag Walton and Lanier
叫你老爹把裁判员带来球场
up and down the court for 48 minutes.
要他们上落跑48分钟吧
Joey... Do you like movies
about gladiators?
祖儿
喜欢关于格斗者电影吗？
Elaine, just hear me out.
绮莲，请听我说
Things haven't been right
for a long time, but it'll be different,
我知道我们之间问题存在已久
但一切将有改变
like in the beginning, remember?
就像开始时那样，记得吗？
I remember everything.
我记得一切
All I have is memories.
我只有回忆
Mostly, I remember the nights
we were together.
记得最深刻的是晚上一起时
I remember how you used to hold me,
我记得你怎样拥抱我
how I used to sit on your face
and wriggle, and...
我怎样坐在你的面上摆动
afterwards, how we'd watch
till the sun came up.
然后我们会一起看日出
When it did, it was almost like...
当太阳升起时
like each new day was created
only for us.
就像那新的一天是为我们而设
That's the way
I've always wanted it to be.
我一直就想这样
But it won't be.
可惜事与愿违
Not as long as you insist
on living in the past!
你一直活在过去！
You're too low, Ted!
泰德，你飞得太低了！
(美军精神病院有戊醇)
The mind plays tricks on you.
你的脑袋又愚弄你了
He looks so happy today, doesn't he?
他今天看来很高兴吧
You look so happy today.
你今天看来很高兴
OK, Robert, slip them down.
This won't hurt much.
罗拔，放他们下来，不痛的
You got a telegram
from headquarters today.
总部今天有电报给你
Headquarters? What is it?
总部？什么来的？
A big building where generals meet,
but that's not important.
即将军聚首的巨型建筑物
算了
They've cleared you of any blame
for what happened on that raid.
那次突击的事，他们不怪责你
- Isn't that good news?
- Is it?
-这岂非好消息？
-是吗？
Because of my mistake,
six men didn't return from that raid.
由于我的过失，有六人死亡
Seven. Lieutenant Zip
died this morning.
是七个，薛中尉今早逝世
But Dr Sandler says you'll be out
in a week. Isn't that wonderful?
但沉医生说你一周后可以出院
这不是好消息吗？
I wish I could say the same
for George Zip.
但愿我能这样跟薛佐治说
Be patient, Ted. Nobody expects you
to get over this immediately.
耐心一点吧！
没有人预期你会立即忘记此事
Hey, Striker, how about a break?
I'm getting tired.
史，可否歇一歇？我很累
Yeah, all right. Take five.
好的，休息五分钟吧
Thanks.
谢谢你
I found a wonderful apartment for us.
It has a brick fireplace
我为我们找到新房子
有砖造的火炉
and a cute bedroom
with mirrors on the ceiling and...
睡房也很特别，天花板有镜子
Red Leader, I'm going down!
红队长，我要下去了！
Captain Geline. He thinks he's a pilot,
still fighting the war.
姬上尉以为自己是机师
仍在打仗
I've found the tunnel, Johnson!
It's this way!
我找到隧道了，这边
$25 for a cigarette is too much!
二十五元一根烟太贵了！
- What's his problem?
- It's Lieutenant Hurwitz.
-他怎么了？
-他是胡中尉
Severe shell shock.
He thinks he's Ethel Merman.
严重弹震症
以为自己是雄性人鱼
War is hell.
战争实在可怕
Excuse me, sir. Would you like
some coffee before dinner?
先生，吃晚餐前想喝杯咖啡吗
No. No, thank you.
不用了，谢谢
- Would you like another cup?
- I will, but Jim won't.
-要多一杯吗？
-好的，但占不要了
I think I will have
another cup of coffee.
我想要多杯咖啡
Jim never has a second
cup of coffee at home.
占在家从来不会多要一杯咖啡
- Excuse me, Sister.
- Yes?
-修女
-什么事？
- There's a little girl on board who's ill.
- Oh, yes, I saw. Poor child.
-机上有一名病重的小女孩
-她真可怜
Could I borrow your guitar?
I thought I'd cheer her up.
我想借你的结他去令她开心点
- Of course.
- Thank you.
-好的
-谢谢你
- Hi.
-你好
Do you mind if I talk
to your daughter?
我可否跟你女儿谈谈？
I think that'd be nice.
随便
- Hi, I'm Randy.
- I'm Lisa. Oh, you have a guitar!
-你好，我叫兰迪
-我是莉莎，你有结他
I thought maybe you'd
like to hear a song.
想听歌吗？
I'd love to.
好！
OK. Let's see...
让我想想
This is one of my favorites.
这是我最喜欢的
You're late. We've been waiting.
你迟到，我们在等你
- Who's first?
- Go ahead, Clarence.
-谁先？
-你来吧！家伦
How's the weather?
天气怎样？
We got some heavy stuff ahead of us.
We've got to climb on top.
前面有厚云层，要上升飞行
Yeah, after the war, I wanted
to get as far away as possible,
战后我想尽量离开伤心地
so Elaine and I
joined the Peace Corps.
故我和绮莲加入和平大使计划
We were assigned
to an isolated tribe, the Molombos.
我们被派往接触偏远部族
莫林保人
They'd never seen Americans before.
他们从没见过美国人
It was really a challenge, introducing
them to our Western culture.
向他们介绍西方文化
是一个大挑战
At first, they didn't know
what to think of us.
起初，他们对我们有戒心
But soon, we gained their trust.
但很快我们获得他们信任
It'll help you better
prepare storing foods
这样保存食物更好
for the up and coming
monsoon months.
可保留至季候风月份
Also, Supperware products
are ideal for storing leftovers
这些用来存放吃剩的东西最好
to help stretch your food dollar.
价廉物美
This two-quart
"Seals-M-Rite" container
这个保鲜盒
keeps hot dog buns fresh for days.
可以令热狗包保持新鲜多天
These people had been completely
isolated from civilization.
这些人一直与文明隔绝
No one had outlined a physical
fitness program for them,
从没有人替他们制订保健计划
and they had no athletic equipment.
他们亦没有运动器材
I started them on simple calisthenics,
worked up to rudimentary game skills,
我教他们做柔软体操
和一些基本球技
and finally,
advanced competitive theory.
最后令他们有竞赛能力
I was patient,
and they were eager to learn.
我很有耐性，他们亦很好学
They seemed to enjoy themselves.
他们似乎玩得很开心
Probably due to advanced
American teaching techniques,
大概因为有先进的美国教法
we bridged the generations
of isolation,
他们再不与世隔绝
and communicated successfully
with the Molombos.
我们成功与莫林保人沟通
They're getting the hang of it. When we
re-enlist, I'll teach them baseball.
他们已把握到个中精髓
再来时，我会教他们打棒球
Ted, I don't want to stay here.
泰德，我不想留在这里
It's time to go home to the plans
we made before the war.
该回家实行战前定下的计划
A lot of people made plans
before the war. Like George Zip.
很多人在战前都有很多计划
薛佐治就是其中一分子
At that moment, I realised Elaine
had doubts about our relationship.
那刻我知道绮莲对我们的
关系有疑问
And that, as much as anything else,
led to my drinking problem.
这引起我的饮水问题
We did come back to the States.
I tried a number of jobs.
我们返美，我做过很多工作
I could go on,
but I'd probably bore you.
我可以继续说，但你会闷坏
I really couldn't blame Elaine.
She wanted a career.
实在不能怪责绮莲
她想有自己的事业
- I can't stand it.
- What is it?
-我受不了
-什么事？
- Yes?
- It's my stomach.
-什么事？
-我的胃很不舒服
I haven't felt this awful since we saw
that Ronald Reagan film.
自从看过列根那电影后
我从没试过那么不舒服
I'll see if I can find some Dramamine.
且看我能否找到晕机药
Captain, a woman passenger
is very sick.
机长，有一名女乘客很不舒服
- Airsick?
- I think so, I've never seen it so acute.
-晕机？
-不是，她真的很辛苦
Find out if there's a doctor on board,
as quietly as you can.
悄悄地找找机上有没有医生
Joey, have you ever been
in a Turkish prison?
祖儿，你到过土耳其监狱吗？
I shouldn't have had
that second cup of coffee.
我不该喝第二杯咖啡
Jim never vomits at home.
占在家从不呕吐
Sorry to wake you. I'm looking for a
doctor. There's nothing to worry about.
抱歉弄醒你，但我想找医生
Stewardess, I think
the man next to me is a doctor.
小姐，我身旁的该是医生
Sir, excuse me. Sorry to wake you,
are you a doctor?
先生，抱歉弄醒你
但你是医生吗？
- That's right.
- We have sick passengers.
-是的
-我们有乘客不舒服
- Could you take a look at them?
- Yes, of course.
-可否去看看他们？
-好的
Let me see your tongue.
让我看看你的舌头
I'll be back in a minute.
我很快回来
Tell the captain to land.
She must go to a hospital.
叫机长降落，要送她往医院
A hospital! What is it?
医院！什么？
It's a big building with patients,
but that's not important.
是一座有病人的建筑物，算了
- I must speak to the captain.
- Certainly.
-我得跟机长谈谈
-好的
Victor, we're running into heavy...
伟达，我们遇上浓…
Roger, take over!
罗渣，快接手！
- Captain, how soon can you land?
- I can't tell.
-机长，何时可以降落？
-我不知道
- You can tell me. I'm a doctor.
- No, I'm not sure.
-你该知道的，我是医生
-不，我不清楚
- Can't you take a guess?
- Not for another two hours.
-可否猜一猜？
-起码两小时之后吧
You can't take a guess
for another two hours?
你要在两小时后才去猜一猜？
No, we can't land.
Fog has closed down everything.
我们无法降落，太大雾了
We've got to get through to Chicago.
我们得尽快降落
Get him out of there!
带他走
- What is it, Doctor? What's going on?
- I'm not sure.
-医生，究竟发生什么事？
-我不清楚
Haven't seen anything like this
since the Anita Bryant concert.
自拜恩的演唱会后
从未见过这种事
- What did we have for dinner?
- We had a choice - steak or fish.
-我们晚餐吃什么？
-可以选牛扒或鱼
Yes, I remember. I had lasagna.
我记得，我吃烤宽面条
- What did he have?
- He had fish.
-他吃了什么？
-吃了鱼
Doctor, two more are sick.
The other passengers are worried.
医生，又有两人不舒服
乘客都很担心
I'll handle the passengers.
我会处理
Find out what the sick people had for
dinner. This is Captain Oveur speaking.
找出病人晚餐吃过什么
我是欧机长
It's bumpy, but we'll be past it
in a few minutes.
我们遇上气流但很快会没事
We're now flying over Hoover Dam,
我们正飞越胡佛水霸
and later we'll pass
south of the Grand Canyon.
跟着我们会飞越大峡谷
Meanwhile, relax
and enjoy your flight, OK?
与此同时，请放松
好好享受今次旅程
Chicago, this is flight 209er.
We're in trouble.
芝加哥，这是209号班机
我们有麻烦
Have all traffic below us cleared.
I want a priority landing in Chicago.
请给我们优先降落权
Yes?
什么事？
My husband's very sick.
Can you do something?
我的丈夫很不舒服，请帮忙
The doctor will be with you
in just a moment.
医生很快会来
- Do you know what he had for dinner?
- Yes, we both had fish. Why?
-知否他晚餐吃了什么？
-我们都吃了鱼，为什么？
It's nothing to be alarmed about.
We'll be back to you very quickly.
没什么，我们很快回来
Doctor, Mr Hammen ate fish,
医生，夏先生吃了鱼
and Randy said there are five
more cases, and they all had fish.
兰迪说又有五人不舒服
他们全都吃过鱼
The co-pilot had fish.
What did the navigator have?
副机师也吃了鱼
导航员吃过什么？
He had fish.
也是吃过鱼
All right, now we know
what we're up against.
好，现在知道什么一回事了
Every passenger who had fish for
dinner will soon become violently ill.
吃过鱼的人都十分不适
- Just how serious is it?
- Extremely serious.
-有多严重？
-极之严重
It starts with a slight fever,
dryness of the throat.
首先会些微发烧，喉咙干涸
When the virus penetrates,
the victim becomes dizzy,
当病毒进一步入侵
病人会觉得晕眩
and begins to experience
an itching rash.
感到浑身痕痒
From there, the poison works
on the central nervous system,
跟着病毒会入侵中央神经系统
causing severe muscle spasms,
followed by the inevitable drooling.
令肌肉严重抽筋
不能自控地流口水
At this point,
the digestive system collapses,
这时消化系统会完全崩溃
accompanied
by uncontrollable flatulence.
肠胃气胀
Until the poor bastard is reduced to
a quivering, wasted piece of jelly.
之后那病人会浑身乏力
有如一堆果冻
(第11行至21行
第13行至51行)
Put it on... automatic pilot.
开启…自动机师
Automatic pilot, automatic pilot...
There it is!
自动机师…在这里了！
I'll go back to the passengers.
我去看看乘客如何
Come in, 209er. This is Chicago.
209号班机，请回答
Flight 209er, come in.
This is Elaine Dickinson,
the stewardess.
我是空中小姐狄绮莲
Captain Oveur's passed out. We've
lost the co-pilot and navigator, too.
欧机长昏倒了
副机师和导航员亦然
- We're in trouble.
- Roger.
-我们有麻烦
-收到
I'm Steve McCroskey,
Chicago air control.
我是芝加哥航空署的麦斯堤
I'll be back in a minute.
Hold all takeoffs.
我很快会跟你再联络
暂停所有航机起飞
When 508 reports, bring it straight in.
508会报时，立即接进来
Suspend all meal service
on flights out of Los Angeles.
暂停由洛杉矶起程的
航机的三餐供应
Tell all dispatchers
to remain at their posts.
叫所有调度员留在岗位
- How about coffee?
- No, thanks.
-喝杯咖啡吗？
-不用了，谢谢
I want the weather
on every available landing field.
我要所有可能降落地点的
天气报告
You understand?
懂吗？
Any place available
to land that plane!
有没有可以降落的地方？
Go to the tower
and get a runway diagram.
往控制塔，找来跑道图
Check down the field
for emergency equipment.
找来紧急事故器材
Chief, we got fog every place
east of the Rockies.
洛杉矶以东所有地方都有雾
They'll have
to come through to Chicago.
他们得来芝加哥降落
Looks like I picked the wrong week
to quit smoking.
似乎我不该在这星期戒烟
Get the best available man
who won't crack under pressure.
找泰山崩于前而不动声色的人
How about Mr Rogers?
罗先生如何？
Get me Rex Kramer.
找祈力斯来
Next to the throttle
is the airspeed gauge.
在节流杆旁的便是速度计
What speed does it indicate?
现在是什么速度？
520 miles per hour.
每小时520哩
Good. Very good.
Now, check your altitude.
好，很好，现在查看高度
That's the dial below and right
of the airspeed indicator.
即是速度计右下方的针盘
35,000 feet.
三万五千英尺
No, wait. 34,000 feet.
不，慢着，三万四千英尺
No. It's dropping!
It's dropping fast!
不，不断下降，下降得很快
Why is it doing that?
为何这样？
Oh, my God! The automatic pilot,
it's deflating!
天啊！自动机师正在泄气
Elaine, don't panic.
绮莲，别恐慌
On his belt line
there's a hollow tube.
它的腰带有一支管
That's the manual inflation nozzle.
Pull it out and blow on it.
是吹气孔，拔它出来吹气吧！
What the hell's going on up there?
究竟发生什么事？
- Elaine.
- Yes, Doctor.
-绮莲
-是，医生
You're a member of this crew.
你是这航机的一员
- Can you face some unpleasant facts?
- No.
-能否接受可怕事实？
-不能
Unless we hospitalise
those people quickly,
除非赶快送这些人往医院
I can't be sure of saving their lives.
否则我不知道能否救他们
Is there anyone on board
who can land this plane?
机上有没有人可以令飞机降落
No one I know of.
据我所知就没有
You ought to know our chances.
Our lives depend on just one thing -
该明白航机上
所有人的生死存亡
finding someone to fly this plane
who didn't have fish for dinner.
取决于可以找到一个懂驾飞机
又没有吃过鱼的人
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is your stewardess speaking.
各位，我是空中小姐
We regret any inconvenience
the sudden cabin movement caused.
刚才机舱震动，对不起
This is due to periodic air pockets.
这是因为遇上气流
There's no reason to become alarmed.
We hope you enjoy your flight.
请别担心，好好享受旅程
By the way, is there anyone on board
who can fly a plane?
此外，有没有人懂驾驶飞机？
Hello. I'm Paul Carey from the airline.
I'm here to pick up Captain Kramer.
我是航空公司的贾保罗
是来接祈上尉的
Yes. Come in, Paul.
Rex will be right out.
请进，力斯很快会出来
Shep, sit. Sit!
羊羊，坐下！
I understand there's an emergency.
我知道这是急事
Something like that. There wasn't time
to tell me very much...
诸如此类，我也不大清楚
Shep, no!
羊羊，不要！
I'll bet exciting things happen
all the time down there.
你们经常遇上刺激的事吧
The airline business
does have its moments.
航空事业确有其精彩时刻
After a while, you get used to it.
稍后你自会适应
Shep! Come!
羊羊，来！
He gets so excited
when new people are here.
有新访客来到，它就很兴奋
- Are you a pilot?
- No, I'm in...
-你是机师吗？
-不是，我…
a training program.
正接受训练
It's unbelievable.
It's just unbelievable.
难以置信
How many times have I warned
about food inspection?
已警告过你多少遍要检查食物
You'd think
someone would listen to you.
还以为有人会听你说
Well, airport management,
the FAA, and the airlines...
机场管理层、飞管局
和航空公司…
they're all cheats and liars.
他们都是骗子
All right. Let's get out of here.
好，走吧
I'm sorry, I was just looking
for someone with flying experience.
抱歉，我想找懂驾驶飞机的人
When they built those roads,
they didn't think about drainage,
他们筑路时，没考虑去水问题
so we had to take a special jeep
up to the main road.
故我们要乘特制吉普车往大路
We were lucky to get a jeep,
since, just the day before,
很幸运我们找来吉普车
the only one we had broke down.
It had a bad axle...
之前一天
我们那辆吉普车坏了
Excuse me, sir.
There's a problem in the cockpit.
先生，驾驶舱有些问题
The cockpit? What is it?
驾驶舱？什么？
The little room where the pilot sits.
That's not important.
即机师坐的小房子，算了
The first officer is ill. The captain needs
someone to help him with the radio.
副机师病倒了
机长想找人帮忙
Do you know anything about planes?
你对飞机有认识吗？
I flew in the war years ago.
多年前我在战时驾驶战机
- I wouldn't know anything about it.
- Would you go up, please?
-我不懂得驾驶飞机
-可否跟我来？拜托
The stewardess said...
那空姐说…
- Both pilots?
- Can you fly this plane and land it?
-两名机师？
-你能否令这飞机降落？
- Surely, you can't be serious.
- I am serious, and don't call me Shirley.
-你说笑吧？
-我是认真的，请别推辞
Doctor, I've checked everyone.
Mr Striker's the only one.
医生，我问过所有人
只有史先生合适
- What's your flying experience?
- I flew single-engine fighters.
-你有什么飞行经验？
-我驾驶过单引擎战机
This plane has four engines.
It's an entirely different kind of flying.
这飞机有四个引擎
是截然不同的飞行经验
It's an entirely different
kind of flying.
是截然不同的飞行经验
I haven't touched
any kind of plane in six years.
我已有六年没接触任何飞机
Mr Striker,
I know nothing about flying.
史先生，我并不懂得驾驶飞机
But I do know that you're the only one
on this plane who can possibly fly it.
但我知道你是飞机上
唯一可能驾驶它的人
You're the only chance we've got.
你是我们唯一的希望
That's right. That's what I said.
You heard me.
对，我也这样说
Tell Omaha to acknowledge
and stand by.
叫奥马哈准备
Every piece of emergency equipment
you can reach.
找来一切应急工具
Alert every rescue unit
from here to the Rockies.
通知由这里至洛矶山的
所有拯救单位
Chief!
首领！
- We'll need a free-landing flight check.
- It's your wife.
-我们要检查自动降落航机
-是你的太太
I want the kids in bed by nine, the dog
fed, the yard watered, the gate locked.
我要孩子九时上床、喂好狗儿
替院子洒水、锁上大闸
Get a note to the milkman -
"No more cheese."
给送牛奶人便条，不再要芝士
Where the hell is Kramer?
祈力斯呢？
No, he can't do that.
The risk of a flame-out's too great.
不，他做不来，起火机会太大
Keep him at 24,000... No, feet.
要他保持在二万四千英尺高
A passenger is
going to land that plane.
一名乘客打算令航机降落
- Is that possible?
- It's a hundred to one shot.
-有可能吗？
-机会微乎其微
- I know this guy.
- You do? Who is it?
-我认识这人
-真的？他是何方神圣？
Ted Striker. I flew with him during
the war. It won't make my job easier.
史泰德，我在战时曾与他合作
但他越帮越忙
Ted Striker was a crack
flight leader, up to a point.
史泰德是个不济飞行小组队长
He was one of those men who...
felt too much inside.
他是那种…太感性的人
Maybe you know that kind.
或许你也认识那种人
He went all to pieces
on a particular mission.
有一次任务，他一败涂地
Let's just hope
that doesn't happen tonight.
希望今晚不会这样
Let's see... Altitude, 24,000 feet.
让我看看…高度，二万四千英尺
Level flight. Speed, 520 knots.
保持这高度，速度520
Course Zero Niner Zero.
航道090
Trim, mixture.
Wash, soap, rinse, spin.
切条、搅均
洗净、冲水、摇干
Ted! What are you doing here?
You can't fly this plane!
泰德，你在此做什么？
你不能驾驶这飞机！
That's what I'm trying to tell them.
我正努力告诉他们这一点
Elaine. I don't have time to be gentle,
so I'll be very direct.
绮莲，我没时间转弯抹角
得直接对你说
Everyone is in a desperate situation.
大家的情况都很危险
Mr Striker is the only hope we got.
史先生是我们唯一的希望
Those are the flaps.
This is the thrust.
那些是襟翼，这是推力
This must turn on the landing lights.
这会亮起降落灯
(返回座位)
- Mayday! Mayday!
- Mayday? What the hell is that?
-救命！…
-五月？怎么了？
May Day's the Russian new year.
We'll have a big parade and serve...
五月是俄罗斯的新年
我们有大巡游
I can't stand it any more.
我不能再忍受了
I've got to get out of here!
我要出去！
- Calm down! Get ahold of yourself!
- Please let me handle this.
-冷静！控制自己
-让我来吧
Calm down. Get back to your seat.
I'll take care of this.
冷静，返回座位，我会处理
Calm down. Get ahold of yourself.
冷静，控制自己
Doctor, you're wanted on the phone.
医生，有人找你
- Everything will be all right.
- Sister, I can handle this.
-一切会没事的
-修女，让我来
Got to get out of here!
走开！
We'd like you to have this flower.
我们想你收下这朵花
Excuse me, sir, would you...
先生，你可否…
Donations for Reverend Moon?
向蒙牧师捐献？
Jews for Jesus?
犹太耶稣？
Read about Jehovah's Witnesses?
耶和华证人？
How about Buddhism?
佛教又如何？
Help Jerry's kids?
救救谢利的孩子？
- Scientology?
- For nuclear power?
-科学教派？
-为核能？
(自助行李提取)
Your attention, please.
No-frills passengers now arriving.
各位注意，乘客正在抵达
Please have your baggage
claim checks ready to show
请在离开机场前
upon leaving the terminal.
提取及检查行李
This guy has no airline experience.
他没有驾驶航机经验
He's a menace to everything in the air.
Yes, birds, too.
他在空中对一切构成危险
包括雀鸟在内
OK, he's a terrible risk,
but what other choice have we got?
他是一大危机
但我们别无他选
That's the whole story, Rex.
Everything we know.
我们所知的就这么多
Let's face a few facts.
I flew with Striker during the war.
告诉你，我曾在战时与史合作
He can't afford to worry about those
times when... things weren't so good.
当事情不顺利，他就方英寸大乱
- Right now things aren't so good.
- Let me tell you something.
-现在事情亦不顺利
-让我告诉你
Striker was a top-notch
squadron leader long ago.
史泰德很久之前
是空军部队队长
Get on the horn
and talk that guy down.
去说服他吧！
Let him get the feel
of that airplane,
让他有信心驾驶飞机
then you'll have to talk him
right down to the ground.
然后令他安全着陆吧！
- Very well. Put Striker on the speaker.
- Use my radio.
-好，联络史泰德吧！
-用我的无线电
I picked the wrong week
to quit drinking.
我不该选这星期戒酒
You can work them direct
from here, Captain.
上尉，你由此直接跟他们说吧
Striker? Striker, this is
Captain Rex Kramer speaking.
史泰德，我是祈力斯上尉
Yes, Captain Kramer.
Read you loud and clear.
我听到，祈上尉
All right.
It's obvious you remember me.
很好，你仍记得我
What do you say we forget about
everything, except what we must do?
不如我们忘记一切，放眼现在
Let's not kid each other, Kramer.
少来这套了
You know I've never flown a bucket
like this. I'll need all the luck there is.
你也知我从没驾驶过这种飞机
一切唯有靠运气
Stand by, Striker.
准备好，史泰德
Our one hope is to build this man up.
I've got to give him confidence.
我们要令他有自信
觉得自己可以胜任
- You ever flown a multi-engine plane?
- No, never.
-驾驶过多引擎飞机吗？
-从来没有
Shit! It's a goddamn waste of time.
岂有此理！这简直浪费时间
- There's no way he can land it!
- You got to talk him down!
-他没可能令飞机降落
-你得说服他！
Route him into Lake Michigan.
At least avoid killing innocent people.
叫他飞往密芝根
这样不会连累无辜
You're the only chance they've got.
你是他们唯一的希望
All right.
好吧
Striker, you listen,
and you listen close.
史，你好好听着
Flying a plane
is like riding a bicycle.
驾驶飞机就像骑单车一样
It'sjust harder to put baseball cards
in the spokes. Get the feel of the plane.
只不过是较复杂一些
你得掌握个中窍门
Later, we'll run down
the landing procedure.
稍后我们会教你着陆程序
All right.
Disengage the automatic pilot.
好，先拆去自动机师
Make no violent control movements
like you did in the fighter planes.
就像你驾驶战机时般
别令飞机强烈摆动
All right.
I'll unlock the automatic pilot.
好，我会放走自动机师
The controls will feel very heavy
compared to a fighter.
操纵杆会比战机的重
Don't worry about that.
It's perfectly normal.
别担心，这是正常的
Now, one more thing.
有一件事
Can somebody work the radio
and leave you free for flying?
可否找人来负责无线电通讯？
- The stewardess is here with me.
- Have her sit in the co-pilot seat.
-空姐就在我旁
-她可以坐到副机师位置
Elaine, he wants you
to sit in the co-pilot seat.
绮莲，他想你坐到副机师座位
What's going on?
We have a right to know the truth.
发生什么事？我们有权知道
All right, I'll level with you all.
好，我会向你们坦白
The most important thing
is that you remain calm.
最重要是保持冷静
There's no reason to panic.
绝对不用惊慌
It's true one of the crew members is ill.
我们确有一名机员病倒
Slightly ill.
有些少不舒服
The other two pilots are fine.
但另外两名机师没事
They're flying the plane, free to pursue
a life of religious fulfilment.
他们正在驾驶飞机，全力以赴
The radio is all yours. Keep an eye
on number three engine gauge.
你来负责无线电通讯
留意第三号引擎表板
It's running a little hot.
有点热
(有点热)
Striker, first I'd like to say something.
史，首先我要说…
I know things must look
pretty rough up there.
我知道现在你那处一定一团糟
If you do what I tell you
when I tell you,
但若你一切都依我的
there's no reason
you should lack confidence
你不该没有自信
in your chances of coming out
alive and in one piece.
你绝对做得到的
What weather are you in?
天气如何？
- Rain.
- And a little ice.
-有雨
-还有些冰雹
And a little ice.
还有些冰雹
- How's it handling?
- Sluggish. Like a wet sponge.
-情况怎样？
-不大好，湿透了
Sluggish. Like a wet sponge.
不大好，湿透了
All right, Striker.
You're doing just fine.
史泰德，你做得很好
It's damn good
he doesn't know I hate his guts.
幸好他不知道我很讨厌他
It's damn good
you don't know he hates your guts.
幸好你不知道我很讨厌你
Can I get you something?
有什么可以帮忙？
I'm sorry. I don't understand.
抱歉，我不明白
- Stewardess. I speak jive.
- Good.
-小姐，我懂说非洲话
-好极了
He said he's in great pain, and he
wants to know if you can help him?
他说很痛苦，想你帮助他
Tell him to relax.
I'll be back with some medicine.
叫他放松，我拿药来
Just hang loose, blood.
She'll get some medicine.
放松，她会拿药来
My Mama didn't raise no dummies,
that's obvious.
我并非省油的灯
Cut me some slack, Jack.
别说废话了
Chump don't want no help,
chump don't get the help.
他不想帮忙…
That dude's got no brains, anyhow.
那厮是没有脑袋的
Let Captain Oveur's wife
know what's going on.
通知欧机长的太太吧！
This weather bulletin
just came off the wire.
刚收到最新的天气报告
- What can you make out of this?
- This?
-你认为怎样？
-这个？
I can make a hat or a brooch
or pterodactyl...
我可以用来做帽子
胸针或无尾飞机…
- Hello?
- Mrs Oveur?
-你好
-欧太太？
Yes, this is Mrs Oveur.
对，我是
This is Ed Macias at the airport.
There's trouble on your husband's flight.
我是机场的马艾迪
你丈夫的航机遇上麻烦
We don't know how serious it is,
我们并不知道情况有多严重
but Steve McCroskey thought
you'd want to come over.
但麦斯堤认为你最好来这里
Yes. I'll be right down.
好，我立即来
I've got to go to the airport. You can
let yourself out the back door.
我得往机场，你由后门走吧
There's juice in the refrigerator.
冰箱里有果汁
Doctor says the sick people are getting
worse. We're running out of time.
医生说病人情况转坏
我们时间无多了
I've got to concentrate.
我得集中精神
Hello?
有人吗？
Echo!
回音！
Pinch hitting for Pedro Bourbone,
拳打柏度
Manny Mota.
脚踢文尼
- How you doing, honey?
- Jack, I'm so hot, I'm burning up.
-老婆，怎么了？
-我很热，像被火烧
I'll turn on some air.
我开窗吧
- What's going on?
- Close the window!
-发生什么事？
-关窗！
Chicago, the passengers
are panicking. When do we start down?
乘客开始恐慌
何时可以降落？
Not yet. You'll be in radar range
any second now.
还未可以
你该快进入雷达范围了
They should have been in range
10 minutes ago.
他们该在十分钟前已进入范围
Gunderson, check the radar range.
Anything yet?
古达臣，再查看雷达
有何发现？
About two more minutes, chief.
尚要两分钟
- They could be miles off course.
- Impossible! They're on instruments.
-他们可能偏离了航道
-没可能！是自动导航！
This is going to be a real sweat.
今次一定很惊险
Gunderson,
let me know when you get anything.
古达臣，有最新消息就通知我
- Got a cigarette, Nels?
- I can't take much more of this.
-尼斯，有香烟吗？
-我再也受不了
Looks like I picked the wrong week
to quit amphetamines.
似乎我选错这星期戒安非他命
- How about some more coffee?
- No, thanks.
-喝点咖啡吗？
-不用，谢谢
These reporters want a statement.
这些记者想你发表声明
- How much longer can they hold out?
- 30, 45 minutes.
-他们能支持多久？
-三十到四十五分钟
- Who's flying the plane?
- A passenger.
-由谁来驾驶飞机？
-一名乘客
He's an experienced air-force pilot.
No cause for alarm. Take over.
他是一名富经验的空军机师
不用担心，你来吧
- What kind of plane?
- It's a big, pretty white plane
-是怎样的飞机？
-又大又漂亮的白色飞机
with red stripes, curtains
and wheels. It looks like a big Tylenol.
有红色条子、窗帘、轮子
就像一架大模型
OK, boys. Let's get some pictures.
好，拿些照片吧！
(航机乘客大难临头)
(芝加哥机长作出最坏打算)
(男孩被困在冰箱
吃掉自己的脚)
(危机)
This bulletinjust handed to me.
Stricken airliner approaching Chicago.
最新消息，那航机飞往芝加哥
Shana, they bought their tickets.
他们自作自受
They knew what
they were getting into.
他们早知道有危险
I say, let them crash!
让航机坠毁吧
- Would you like some whisky, ma'am?
- Certainly not!
-要威士忌吗？
-不要
How are the passengers?
乘客怎么样？
I won't deceive you, Mr Striker.
We're running out of time.
我不会骗你，我们时间无多了
- Surely, there's something you can do.
- I'm doing everything I can...
-你一定可以做什么的
-我已尽一切办法…
and stop calling me Shirley.
也不要再说我有办法
Randy, are you all right?
兰迪，你没事吧？
Oh, Dr Rumack.
雷医生
I'm scared. I've never been so scared...
我很害怕，从没这般害怕
And besides,
I'm 26 and I'm not married.
而且我26岁了，还未结婚
We're going to make it.
You've got to believe that.
我们定会成功的，你定要相信
Dr Rumack, do you have any idea
when we'll be landing?
雷医生，知否我们何时着陆？
Pretty soon. How are you bearing up?
快了，你觉得怎样？
To be honest,
I've never been so scared,
坦白说，我从来没那么惊慌过
but at least I have a husband.
但幸好我有丈夫
Stay in formation.
Target'sjust ahead.
保持队形，目标就在前面
Target should be clear
if you go in low enough.
若飞得够低，该能看清楚目标
You'll have to decide.
你得决定…
你得决定
Stay in formation.
Target'sjust ahead.
保持队形，目标就在前面
Target should be clear
if you go in low enough.
若飞得够低，该看清楚目标
You'll have to decide.
你得决定…
你得决定
Oh, rats! Lost number four.
糟糕！四号引擎没有了
What happened? What went wrong?
发生什么事？有何不妥？
I forgot to check the oil pressure.
我忘了检查油压
When Kramer hears about this,
the shit's going to hit the fan.
若给祈力斯知道，定给他臭骂
I told him to watch that
oil temperature. What's he doing?
早叫他检查油压，他怎么了？
Stiker, that plane can't land itself.
史泰德，飞机无法自行降落
Ease off. It's not his fault.
It could happen to any pilot.
这不是他的错
任何机师都可能会这样
It happened to Barbara Stanwyck.
施丹域亦出现这情形
Can't push him too hard. Might break.
Remember who you're dealing with.
别逼得他太紧，他可能会崩溃
Nick, Pete, Jerry,
there's a fire in the barn.
尼克、彼得、谢利，紧急状态
He's right.
I can't take the pressure.
他说得对，我应付不了压力
I was crazy to think
I could land this plane.
我以为可以令飞机降落
实在妄想
- But, Ted, you're the only...
- I don't care. I don't have what it takes.
-泰德，只有你…
-我不管，我没有这个能力
They'd be better off with someone
who's never flown before.
找过从没驾驶过飞机的人来
结果可能更好
Bad news. Fog's getting thicker.
坏消息，雾越来越浓
And Leon's getting larger.
李安亦越来越大
I know what you're going to say,
so save your breath.
我知道你想说什么，省口气吧
Well, I don't have a thing to say.
我并没想要说什么
You've done the best you could.
你已尽了力
You really have. The best you could.
真的，你已尽了力
We can't expect to win them all.
凡事岂能尽如人意
I want to tell you something I've
kept to myself through these years.
告诉你我保守了多年的秘密
I was in the war. Medical corps.
我在战时是军医
One night, they brought in
a badly wounded pilot from a raid.
有一晚他们送来一名重伤机师
He could barely talk.
他几乎不能说话
He looked up at me, he said,
但他望着我说
"The odds were against us up there,
but we went in anyway.
“我们形势不利
但还是勇往直前”
"I'm glad.
Captain made the right decision."
“我很高兴
上尉作出正确决定”
The pilot's name was George Zip.
那机师的名字叫做薛佐治
George Zip said that?
薛佐治说的？
The last thing he said to me,
"Doc," he said, "Sometime...
他最后对我说： “医生…”
"...the crew is up against it.
“队员都全力以赴”
"The breaks are beating the boys.
“我们虽然受到挫折”
"Tell them to give it all they've got
“但告诉他们要倾尽全力”
"and win just one for the Zipper.
“为部队胜出一仗”
"I don't know
where I'll be then," he said...
“到时我不知道
自己会身在何处”
"but I won't smell too good,
that's for sure."
“但肯定已全身发臭”
Excuse me, Doc.
医生，失陪
I've got a plane to land.
我要令飞机着陆
You'd better stay up there a bit.
When the fog lifts, we'll bring you in.
留在上空，待大雾消散才降落
I'll take it, Elaine.
绮莲，让我来
Listen, Dr Rumack says the sick
people are in critical condition.
听着，雷医生说病人情况危殆
Every minute counts.
We've got to land now.
每分每秒都很重要
要现在降落了
Don't be a fool, Striker. You know
what a landing like this means.
别傻了
你也知道这样降落结果会如何
I'm ordering you to stay up there!
我命令你继续在上空
No dice, Chicago.
不行
I'm giving the orders,
and we're coming in.
现在由我话事，我们要降落了
I guess the foot's
on the other hand now.
现在他反客为主了
He'll never make it in this soup.
这样大雾，他是不会成功的
But it's his ship now. He's in charge.
但现在由他话事了
He's the boss, head man, top dog,
他是老板、上头、首领…
- big cheese, head honcho...
- Captain, look at this!
-领袖、老大…
-上尉，看！
"Passengers certain to die."
“乘客必死无疑”
"Airline negligent."
“航空当局疏忽”
There's a sale at Penny's!
百货公司大减价！
I'll need three men up in the tower.
You, Neubauer, you, Macias.
我要三人往控制塔
黎保家、马卡斯
Me John. Big tree.
还有我， “大树”约翰
Striker, we're going to the tower.
Good luck.
史，我们准备往控制塔
祝你好运
- We're going to the tower.
- The tower! The tower!
-我们准备往控制塔
-控制塔
Rapunzel! Rapunzel!
林宝素…
Stewardess, how soon till we land?
小姐，尚有多久才降落？
It won't be long now.
Try not to worry.
快了，别担心
We're all ready, sir. Captain
McCroskey, this is Captain Roberts.
我们准备好了
麦机长，这是罗机长
Captain Kramer, Captain Colosimo.
Captain Hinshaw, Captain Gantz.
祈上尉、高机长
韩机长、简机长
Captain Kramer, Captain Gantz.
Captain Hinshaw, Captain Roberts.
祈上尉、简机长
韩机长、罗机长
Colosimo, you work the relay.
高，你负责联络
Roberts, check air traffic.
罗，看看航空交通
Get that finger out of your ear.
You don't know where it's been.
拿出手指来，很脏的
- Steve!
- Got a cigarette, Nels?
-史堤
-尼斯，有香烟吗？
Linda, your husband and the others
are alive but unconscious.
莲黛，你的丈夫
和其他人仍活着，但昏迷了
Just like Gerald Ford.
就像福特
There's a chance we can save them
if Striker lands that plane in time.
若史及时降落
我们便有机会救他们
- That isn't much of a chance, is it?
- I don't know.
-但机会不大吧？
-不知道
We're doing everything we can.
Now excuse me.
我们已尽了力，失陪
Where did you get that dress?
It's awful!
你从哪儿买来这裙子？很难看
And those shoes and that coat! Geez!
还有这对鞋和大衣，天啊！
8 miles. Turn right to heading 044.
八哩，转右往044
We're now at 2,000 feet
beginning our descent.
我们现在于二千英尺上空
开始降落
- Pour every light onto that field.
- It's being done.
-把跑道所有灯亮起
-已经这样做了
Tower to all emergency vehicles,
runway is niner.
控制塔呼叫所有救急汽车
前往九号跑道
Airport vehicles,
take positions one and two.
机场汽车，一、二号准备
Civilian equipment, number three.
平民器材，三号
Air force, positions four and five.
空军，四、五号
All ambulances go to number three.
所有救护车往三号站
Air Israel, please clear the runway.
以色列航机，请驶离跑道
In a moment, we'll ask you
to assume crash positions.
我们将要你们摆出撞击姿势
Life jackets are under your seat.
椅子下面有救生衣
Place it over your head. When I give the
word, pull the cord on the right side flap.
套上去，我一声令下
就拉右面的绳子
Your seat cushions are also equipped
with a flotation device.
你们的椅垫都有浮水设计
WZAZ in Chicago,
where disco lives forever.
芝加哥的WAZA电台
永远为你播放
Your altitude's too erratic.
你的飞行高度忽高忽低
You can't come straight in.
You've got enough fuel for two hours.
不能降落
你尚有两小时的燃料
I'll take it, Elaine.
Listen to me, Kramer.
绮莲，让我来…祈，你听着
We have people up here who will die
in less than an hour.
机上有人在不足一小时后
就会死去
I may bend your airplane,
but I'll get it down.
我或会令飞机损毁
但我可以成功降落的
I'm putting the landing gear down.
我要放下降落架了
- The passengers are ready.
- Thanks, Randy.
-乘客都准备好了
-劳驾
You better leave, sweetheart.
You might get hurt up here.
你还是出去吧！
在这儿你可能会受伤
- Ted...
- Yes?
-泰德
-什么事？
I wanted you to know... now...
我想你知道…现在…
I'm very proud.
我以你为傲
Tell them the gear is down
and we're ready to land.
告诉他们降落架已放下
我们准备降落
The gear is down,
and we're ready to land.
降落架已放下，我们准备降落
All right. He's on final now. Put out
all runway lights except niner.
好，已进入最后阶段
只亮起九号跑道的灯
Captain, maybe we ought
to turn on the searchlights now.
上尉，我们或许该亮起搜索灯
No.
不
That's just what they'll
be expecting us to do.
他们就是以为我们会这样做
I want to tell you both good luck.
We're all counting on you.
祝你们好运，我们全看你们了
Now listen carefully. You'll see
the runway at 300 feet.
小心听着，在三百英尺高度
你便会见到跑道
Aim to touch down a third of the way.
A slight cross wind, so be ready.
在跑道三分一位置时着陆
有微风，准备好
If you land too fast, use your emergency
brakes. Red handle's right in front.
若着陆得太快，用紧急煞掣
即右前方的红色手掣
If that doesn't stop you...
若这样还不停下
If that doesn't stop you,
cut the four ignition switches.
就熄掉四个引擎
Can you see us now? You should
be able to see the field.
看到我们没有？
你该看到机场了
- Sure is quiet out there.
- Yeah, too quiet.
-外面很平静
-对，太平静了
Looks like I picked the wrong week
to quit sniffing glue.
似乎我选错了这星期戒闻胶水
There it is.
它来了！
There he is!
他来了！
- You're coming in too fast.
- I know, I know!
-速度太快了
-我知道…
He knows, he knows!
他知道…
Below 700 now. Still going down.
现在低于七百英尺，仍在下降
675, 650, 625, he's holding.
No, he's down, he's down.
675英尺、650英尺、625英尺
稳住了，不，正下降
Sound your alarm now.
发出警号吧
Now, everybody,
get in crash positions.
大家请准备撞机
Put down 30 degrees of flap.
风门翼要三十度
Listen to me. Remember your brakes
and switches. Get ready to flare it out!
听着，煞掣，按钮，准备
He's all over the place.
900 up to 1,300 feet. What an asshole.
他一时在九百英尺
一时在一千三百英尺，真是笨蛋
More left rudder. Put down more flap.
靠左，风门翼更加偏侧
Just kidding!
开玩笑而已
Striker, lift your nose.
Straighten your wings.
史，升起机头，伸直机翼
Coming in too fast. Watch your speed.
太快了，留意速度
He's coming right at us!
他向我们冲来！
Coming in too hot.
Ease up on the throttle.
太快了，减慢速度
Watch out for that cross wind.
Level it out. Dip your left wing.
留意风向，左翼倾侧
You're drifting. Keep your eyes
on the far end of the runway.
你偏离了航道，望着跑道末端
You're too low, damn it!
太低了，糟糕！
Watch your stall speed.
留意速度
Flare it out!
慢慢降落！
Ease her down. Down!
慢慢让它着陆，着陆吧！
The brake! Pull the red handle!
煞掣！拉那红色手掣！
I want to tell you both good luck.
We're all counting on you.
祝你俩好运，我们全看你们了
Flight 209 now arriving at gate eight.
209号班机正抵达八号闸
Gate nine.
九号闸
Gate ten.
十号闸
Pull out of it! Push that button!
拉！按钮！
Gate 13... Gate 14.
十三号闸，十四号闸
Gate 15...
十五号闸
Auntie Em! Toto! It's a twister!
天啊！它在旋转！
Gate 23, 24, 25...
23号闸，24号闸，25号闸…
I want to tell you both good luck.
We're all counting on you.
祝你俩好运，我们全看你们了
Striker?
史泰德？
- Striker, are you all right?
- Yeah. We're OK.
-史泰德，你没事吧？
-我们没事
That was probably the lousiest landing
in the history of this airport.
这大概是本机场最拙劣的降落
But some of us, particularly me,
但我们有好些人，特别是我
would like to buy you a drink
and shake your hand.
想请你喝东西和与你握手
And, Ted, when the going got rough...
泰德，当遇上困难…
Have a nice day. OK.
祝你愉快
Have a nice day and thank you
for flying TransAmerican.
祝你愉快，多谢乘搭本班航机
Loneliness, that's the bottom line.
I was never happy as a child.
寂寞是底线，儿时我从不快乐
Christmas, what does that mean
to you? Mine was a living hell.
圣诞对你有何意义？
对我来说则是活受罪
Do you know what it's like to fall
in the mud and get kicked in the head
你知否掉在泥泞上
被铁靴踢头…
by an iron boot?
那滋味是怎样的？
Of course not. It never happens. Sorry.
That's a dumb question. Skip that.
当然不知道，因从没发生
抱歉，这条问题真笨
There you go. Have a nice day.
祝你愉快
Municipal bonds, Ted.
I'm talking double "A" rating.
泰德，你实在很出色
Best investment in America.
是美国最佳的投资
完
Well, I'll give him
another 20 minutes, but that's it.
我只会再给他二十分钟
ENGLISH